Finding Aid for the Yoneo Sakai Papers LSC.1426
UCLA Library Special Collections
Yoneo Sakai papers
1848-1979
UCLA Library Special Collections
Sakai, Yoneo
LSC.1426
21.5 Linear Feet (43 boxes and 27 oversize boxes)
Yoneo Sakai (1900-1978) was a editor for Japanese language newspapers in San Francisco, Los Angeles, and New York. He also travelled around the world as a correspondent for Asahi shimbun from 1931 until the outbreak of World War II when he was interned in the Granada Relocation Center. After the war, he was commissioned to teach Japanese at University of Colorado, and hosted a radio program, Amerika Dayori (News from America). The collection consists of Sakai's correspondence, manuscripts, published works, notebooks, and diaries.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Ruby Sakai, 1987-88.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942337203606533
Biography
Sakai was born in 1900 in Saga Prefecture, Kyushu, Japan; studied at Kansai Gakuin and the Meiji Gakuin, majoring in literature; employed by Kokusai Joho Sha in Tokyo as editor of journal, Eiga to engei (Motion pictures and dramas); arrived in San Francisco, 1926, and worked as editor for Japanese language newspapers in San Francisco, Los Angeles, and New York; travelled around the world as a correspondent for Asahi shimbun from 1931 until the outbreak of World War II; dispatched to Manchuria after the Japanese attack; returned to U.S. as official correspondent, 1938; interned during World War II in Granada Relocation Center; commissioned to teach Japanese at University of Colorado; one of Japan's most respected newspaper correspondents, he also hosted a radio program, Amerika Dayori (News from America); interviewees included John F. Kennedy, Lyndon B. Johnson, and Ernest Hemingway; lived in Washington, D.C. from 1946 until his death in 1978.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, manuscripts, published works, notebooks, and diaries of Yoneo Sakai. Also includes photographs of Sakai and his family, as well as photographs and postcards from Spain, the Middle East, California, China, and Japan. Includes Sakai's collection of publications, books, and serials, including an 1848 history of New York. Also contains nineteenth century photographs (some of which are tinted) of various portraits and scenes.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Bibliographical.
Writings.
Graphic material.
Research materials.
Publications not by Sakai.
Diaries.
Manuscripts.
Related Material
Japanese American Research Project (Collection 2010). Available at Library Special Collections, UCLA.
Diaries.; Journalists -- Japan -- Archives.; Photographs.; Sakai, Yoneo -- Archives
- Biographical
  - Correspondence
    - Department of the Navy, 1933-1945. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1942. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Office of War Information, 1942. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - War Relocation Authority, 1942, 1943. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - War Department, 1942-1946. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - McCormick, William, 1942. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Military Intelligence Service Language School, 1943-1948. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Office of Strategic Services, 1945. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Truman, Harry S. / letter from Sakai, 1946. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Japanese American Committee for Democracy, 1946. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Lordsburg, New Mexico. Chamber of Commerce, 1967. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous personal, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Petition, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Sakai, Ruby / Bendetsen, Karl, 1942. (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Affidavit of Mr. Glenn W. Shaw, 1945. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Jokun, primarily, 1971. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - I. Inutsuka, 1973. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Indonesian embassy, 1970.; To Ruby Sakai. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Condolence letters, primarily, 1978. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - The White House dinner, 1965.; Autograph of A. Hitchcock. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Department of State dinner invitation, 1969. (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - The White House dinner invitation, 1965.; On the occasion of the visit of His Excellency Eisaku Sato Prime Minister of Japan. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - U.S. Naval postgraduate school Annapolis, Maryland, 1948.; Termination of excepted appointment at U.S. Naval school (Naval intelligence). (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Roster of the Asahi shimbum alumni, etc. (Tokyo), 1970. (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Postcards, 1962-1963.; Some postcards are from Ruby and Ruri to Yoneo. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Tokyo shinbunsha, 1955, 1956. (Box 29, Folder 19)
      Scope and Content
      Kodama Sokichi, Miyazawa Satoru, Suzuki Norio.
    - Okada, Hideo, 1955[?]. (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Sakai, Benzo, 1955. (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Kuwabara, Sumio, and Sato Kanzan., 1962 (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - Personal letters to and from Mrs. Sakai., 1978-1979 (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - Takehisa, Yumeji, 1949. (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - Sakai Yoneo shishu ni tsuite, 1966. (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - Kunugi bunko; Koga, Ayako; Sankei shimbunsha, etc., 1935-1977. (Box 29, Folder 26)
      Includes letter from Rufus B. von Kleinsmid.
    - Condolence letters, 1978-1981. (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Copies of letters written by Yoneo Sakai, 1945-1980.; Correspondence to War Department, Mrs. Sakai, Department of State, Secretary of Defense, etc. (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Official letters during the war period, 1942.; Navy Intelligence School, War Department, Department of Justice, Time, University of Colorado, Togo Tanaka, etc. (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Letters from American friends and officials, 1945-1980.; The White House, Department of State, Representative S. Stratton, Robert J. McCloskey, etc. (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Letters from Japanese friends, 1957-1980.; Shikanai Nobutaka, Hijikata Masami, Kasai Jiuji, Takehisa Yumeji, etc. (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Art Collections
    - Photographs of Sakai's art collections, with annotations, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Ko Yamaguchi Ryoichi shi jihitsu makimono, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Sakai Yoneo no sho, 1964. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Articles About Sakai
    - Sankei shimbun, 1971.; Jokun (conferment of a decoration). (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Sankei shimbun, 1978.; Sakai Yoneo kisha ga shikyo. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Sankei shimbun, Tokyo shimbun, Rafu shimpo, 1971.; Jokun. (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Sankei shimbun, 1978.; Sakai Yoneo kisha o shinonde. (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - The New York Nichibei, 1971.; Aki no jokun. (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Kyoto shimbunshaho, 1955.; Sakai Yoneo no toji, Vaughan sho. (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Nihon to Amerika, 1971.; pp.14-15. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Seiso, 1966.; pp.40-41. (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Sogo janarizumu (journalism) kenkyu, 1972.; pp.36, 168. (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Sagajin. vol.1 no.1, 1965.; p.23. (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Sagajin. vol.1 no.4, 1965.; pp.6-7. (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Sagajin. vol.2 no.3, 1966.; Article about Sakai, Sakai Yoneo no shishu, pp.1-2; Article by Sakai, Bokyo tsushin, 3, pp.11-16. (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Sagajin. vol.2 no.4, 1966.; 2 items.; Article about Sakai, Kishimyosotekina Sakai Yoneo shishu, p.9; Article by Sakai, Bokyo tsushin, pp.15-18. (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Sagajin. vol.3 no.3, 1967.; Article about Sakai, Watakushi no isho, futatabi, pp.5-8; Article by Sakai, Bokyo tsushin, pp.15-18. (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Dai bizen. vol 44 no.2, 1974; p. 14 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Dai bizen. vol.41 no.11, 1971.; p.23. (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Shukan bunshu. vol.8 no.36, 1966.; pp.94-98.; Interview by Oya Soichi. (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Bungei shunju. vol.42 no.10, 1964.; Photograph of Sakai, Aru kokusai kisha. (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Nippon to Amerika. vol.25 no.10, 1971.; Jokun. (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Sogo janarizumu kenkyu, p. 66., 1972 (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - Sakai Family Portraits
    - Sakai, Yoneo. Photographs, 1927-1968. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Sakai, Ruby. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Sakai, Yoneo. Photographs, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Sakai, Ruby and Ruri (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of Friends, etc.
    - J.F. Kennedy, Chichibunomiya, Dwight Eisenhower, Kotaishidenka and Michiko Hidenka, Daniel Inoue, etc. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Receipts
    - Travel expenses, insurance, etc., 1947-1973. (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Memorabilia
    - Certificate of appreciation by National Press Club, December 11, 1978. (Box 65, Folder 8)
- Writings
  - Publications
    - Shin Amerika dayori. Tokyo: Meikyokudo, 1949. (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Amerika dayori II. Tokyo: Meikyokudo, 1949.; 3 items. (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Amerika dayori III. Tokyo: Meikyokudo, 1950.; 2 items. (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Amerika zakkicho. Tokyo: Itagaki shoten, 1948. (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Vagabondo tsushin. Tokyo: Kaizosha, 1939. (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Zoku Vagabondo tsushin. Tokyo: Kaizosha, 1940. (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Vagabondo Jo. Tokyo: Itagaki shoten, 1948. (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Nikkeishimin to Yuki. Tokyo: Sankei shimbunsha shuppankoku, 1969. (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Sakai Yoneo shishu. Tokyo: Shichosha, 1966.; 2 items. (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - Watakushi no isho. Tokyo: Bungeishunjusha, 1967.; Photocopy. (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - Shukan Shincho, vol. 14, no. 9. (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Shin Kyodo, vol. 7, no. 8., 1954 (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Shin Kyodo, no. 9., 1954 (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Mamizu, vol. 4, no. 1., 1969 (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - Sogo janarizumu kenkyu, 1975 (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - Publications in Serials
    - Tokyo shimbun, 1963.; K-daitoryo no ansatsu, sekai no shogeki; and some source material. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Sankei shimbun, 1971.; Hira tokuhain ichidai, 5. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Sankei shimbun, 1969.; Ogasawara henkan medo shimesu. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Sankei shimbun, n.d.; Gungaku kyodo ni hansei mudo. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Sankei shimbun, 1968.; Perry honichi no tokubetsuten. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Sankei shimbun, 1967.; Beikoku de hirotta muttsu no hiwa. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Sankei shimbun, 1964.; Chukyo no kokuren kamei muri. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Sankei shimbun, 1971.; Nihon no 80nendai ABM haibi. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Sankei shimbun, n.d.; Boru kokumujikan to tandoku kaiken. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Sankei shimbun, 1964.; Funso no kipurosu o yuku. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Sankei shimbun, 1964.; Tairitsu kibishii ryo shuno: Kipurosu seifuku daitoryo to kaiken. (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Rafu shimpo, 1970.; Rafu shimpo 200mango tokushu, cooking, and others. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Time. vol.75 no.4, 1960.; Japan's prime minister Kishi on cover. (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Sankei shimbun, 1967.; Bei kisha no shukaikenki to chukyo no hiteiseimei. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Tokyo shimbun, 1957.; Matsushita tokushi Daresu chokan to kaiken. (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Tokyo shimbun, 1957.; A daitoryo, Kishi hobei o jushi. (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Tokyo shimbun, 1962.; Xgo sakusen no uchimaku. (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Sankei shimbun, 1967.; Bei, gunji atsuryoku o kyoka, Vietnam. (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Tokyo shimbun, 1961.; Asia no tabi kara. (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Sankei shimbun, 1969.; Nichibei kan nimo hottorain (hotline). (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Tokyo shimbun, 1961.; Oshu no tabi kara. (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Sankei shimbun, 1971.; Taiwan kaiketsu...Bei tokyoku, chumoku no hatsugen, hitotsu no chugoku shisa ka. (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Sankei shimbun, 1972.; Bei daitoryo ichiji wa daini no Cuba kakugo. (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Rafu shimpo, 1942.; Zaibei Demokurashi to Zaibei Nihonjin, series. (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Rafu shimpo, n.d.; Danwa shitsu; by Sakai[?]. (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Tokyo shimbun, 1963.; Kennedy daitoryo o itamu. (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Tokyo shimbun, 1957-1960.; Chukyo kinyu no jijitsujo kanwae, etc. (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Sankei shimbun, 1971.; Hira tokuhain ichidai, no.1-23. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Sankei shimbun, 1969.; Okinawa, hayaku kaesubekida: Bei genronkai de iken tsuyomaru. (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Sankei shimbun, 1969.; Kichi, genjo no mamade: Okinawa, Bei no taido. (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Tokyo shimbun, 1951.; Tainichi enjo: Kowa to doji ni uchikiri. (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Sankei shimbun, 1972.; Ingasorushi kiyo: shinraisuji Bei no shin chunichitaishi naitei. (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Sankei shimbun, n.d.; New York made Nikkoki noriire Bei ga judaku no kaito. (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Sankei shimbun, 1972.; Satogaeri suru kigekio Chaplin. (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Nihon to Amerika, n.d.; 40nen no omoide no kazukazu 6: Issei to shite kaiteokitai koto. (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Nihon to Amerika, 1971.; pp.18-19. 2 items.; Tsuioku no hitobito: Miyoshi Juro shi. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Tenbo, 1967.; pp.74-78.; Amerika de yomu Asahi. (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Gendaishi techo, 1967.; pp.91-92.; Jap [poem]. (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Bungei shunju. vol.46 no.6, 1968.; pp.132-140. 2 items.; Genchi hokoku, Kumon suru Washington. (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Sogo janarizumu kenkyu no.30, 1967.; pp.67-70.; Zasshi kisha ni natta daitoryo reijo. (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Sagajin. vol.1 no.3, 1965.; pp.12-14.; Taisho no Saga shimbunkai. (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Sagajin. vol.1 no.5, 1965.; pp.13-14. 2 items.; Bokyo kaiko no Saga. (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Sagajin. vol.2 no.1, 1966.; pp.11-12.; Bokyo tsushin, 2. (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Sagajin. vol.3 no.1, 1967.; pp.14-15.; Bokyo tsushin. (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Sagajin. vol.3 no.2, 1967.; pp.14-15.; Bokyo tsushin. (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Sagajin. vol.4 no.3, 1968.; pp.21-22.; Bokyo tsushin. (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Sagajin. vol.4 no.7, 1968.; pp.12-14.; Bokyo tsushin, 10. (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Hoshi no.14, 1974.; pp.1-3. 2 items.; Sokoku o omou[?]. (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Saga shidan, 1968.; p.28.; Bokyo tsushin. (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Hato Maunten (Heart Mountain) bungei, no. 2, 1944 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Tokyo shimbun, 1954: April-November. (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Sankei shimbun, 1963-1972.; To-ou no tabi, 1-6,8. (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Tokyo shimbun, 1951. (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Shin kyodo, 1953, 1954.; 11 items. (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Sagajin, 1966: July and November.; 2 items.; Bokyo tsushin. (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Saga shidan, 1970, 1972.; 2 items. (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Reviews of Publications
    - Fukei, 1967.; Advertisement of Watakushi no isho, p.13. (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Sankei shimbun, etc., Reviews of Watakushi no isho. (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Shukan asahi, vol.75 no.7, 1970.; Review of Ippon no kugi by Sakai and Hiraga, p.97. (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Nihon to Amerika, etc., Sakai Yoneo shishu, Nikkei shimin to Yuki, Doran no Spain hokoku, Watakushi no isho. (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Manuscripts
    - Yokuryusho no hanashi, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Rohei wa kesshite kienai, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Arumata no hakamairi, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Irukutsuku (Irkutsk) bosan, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Nomura Kichizaburo taishi no hanashi, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Supai (spy) monogatari, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Untitled (Kokutaigoji), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - A-kyu senpan, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Nyujirando (New Zealand) ni okotta Nihonjin horyo sassho jiken (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Kokutaigoji, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Imin no hanashi, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Untitled (Should the Japanese newspapers openly state that they are 100% in cooperation with President...?), n.d.; The Rafu Shimpo letter head. (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Nagai tabiji no hateni, 1938. (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Beikoku no Nikkeijin shakai, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Senzen no noto (note) yori no.1, 1939-1941. (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Senzen no noto (note) yori no.2, 1939-1941. (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Kengaku, Spain naisen kenbun, 1937. (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Nihon no insho, Tokyo homon, 1951, 1966. (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Rozubagu (Lordsburg) jiken, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - America seso no ichimen, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Jiyu no kane, America shoshi, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Kakuheiki to tozai reisen, omoide, daitoryosen, etc., 1965[?].; Hokubei bungeisha genkoyoshi. (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Hajimeni (Sakai Yoneo shishu), Kanto Daishinsai zengo no hanashi, etc., n.d.; Tokyosha genkoyoshi. (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - T chusa supai (spy) jiken, Green Bere (Beret) no Nikkeijin, Seichi no hanashi, etc., 1937-1969.; Sogo journalism kenkyu genkoyoshi. (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Senzen no noto yori, Bei no seso, etc., n.d.; Small size genkoyoshi. (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - CIA, Betonamu (Vietnam) senso, etc., n.d.; Nihon to Amerikasha genkoyoshi. (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Untitled (Okinawa ni okeru zettai shihaiken to...), 1967.; Sakai Yoneo genkoyoshi. (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Kyori no omoide, 1969. (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Untitled (Jiyuboeki o tonaeru Nixon wa...), n.d.; Itoya genkoyoshi. (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Hiratokuhain ichidai, 1971.; Sankei shimbun. (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Okinawa to Ogasawara, Bucharest nite, Warsaw nite, Budapest nite, etc., n.d. (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Ogasawara mondai and untitled miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Notes
    - Bei to Betonamu (Vietnam) kankei, and other miscellaneous notes (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Togo to eijin, Irukutsuku (Irkutsk) no nihonjin bochi, and other miscellaneous notes (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Notebooks
    - China, 1938. (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Iran, Iraq, 1938. (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Senzen no, 1941: April-August. (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Japan, 1973. (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Egypt, Athens, 1937. (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Spain (Madrid), 1937. (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Spain, England (London), 1937. (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Yamashita kisen, Kiyosumi-maru senjo, 1938 November-December. (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Senzen no kanso, 1941: August-November. (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Camp (nai no) seikatsu, 1940-1942.; 3 items. (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Senchu, Nihon no koto o benkyo, 1943. (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Notebooks after World War II, 1953-1974.; 11 items. (Box 67, Folder 5)
- Graphic Material
  - Etchings
    - Miscellaneous, primarily American. (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Negatives
    - Europe, Middle East, etc. Also family portraits. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Photoprints
    - Vietnam, 1937, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Greece, 1937. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Iran, 1938. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Syria, 1937, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Iraq (Baghdad), 1938. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Turkey, 1937. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Egypt (Suez Canal), 1937. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Italy, 1937. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - East Germany, 1964. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Switzerland, 1937. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Palestine, 1937. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Spain, 1937. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Unidentified. (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Unidentified. Reproductions of paintings, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - China. (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - London Bridge. (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - France (Paris). (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Hong Kong. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Japan (Yokohama). (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - California, Oregon landscapes, tinted photographs[?] by Miyoshi Hojin. (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Takehisa, Yumeji. Reproductions of paintings. Owned by Sakai[?]., 2 items. (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Japan, 19th century. (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Italy (Venice) Venezia palazzo ducale: N.20 Fotografie Quadri. (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Portraits, American[?] 19th century. Cartes du visite album. (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Japanese scenes, 19th century[?] tinted photographs in album. Nihon no furui shashin. (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Portraits, American, 19th century salon prints. (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Portraits, scenes, American, 19th century. Furui Amerika no shashin. (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Spain, 1937. (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified, n.d.; Includes reproductions of paintings. (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - President Johnson, 1965.; Includes reviews of Sakai's publication, articles by Sakai, and pictures of unidentified persons with their signatures. (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Jerusalem, Syria, Vietnum, China, Mongoria, and Russia, 1937-1938[?]. (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - President Kennedy, n.d.; Includes photoprints of an astronaut. (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Postcards
    - U.S. National Gallery of Art, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Japan. Celebrated sights of Japan: 72 postcards, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - California, Los Angeles, 1910[?]. (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - California, San Francisco, 1910[?]. (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - California, other, 1910[?]. (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - New York, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Hawaii, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - New Orleans, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - In the tunnel.., n.d. (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Beverly Hills, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Rafu byoin, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Japanese-American men, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - A house with palm trees, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Scenery, a road with newly planted palm trees, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Spain. (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Hungary. (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Japan. (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Basque region. (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Italy. (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Portugal (Lisbon). (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - France (Paris). (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Iraq (Baghdad museum). (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Korea (occupied by Japan). (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Russia (Moscow). (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Japan. Ruby no nihon ehagaki. (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Stamps, Banknotes, Tickets, etc.
    - Japan, Spain, America, etc. Furui sutanpu. (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Stereographs
    - Japan. Nihon no shashin. (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - American stories: Marriage, the holy bond of love, Love at first sight, etc. Amerika no shibai no shashin. (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Spanish - American war, Russo - Japanese war. Senso no shashin. (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - American scenes. Amerika keshiki no shashin. (Box 38, Folder 1)
- Research Materials
  - Index to the Konoye documents (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Japanese surrender documents, 1945. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Nuclear discontinuance, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Outline of Asian nations, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Johnson/Sato dyodoseimei, 1967. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - George Ball interview, 1965. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Kusama, Yayoi, 1968[?]. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Taiwan problems, 1958. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Tenno ni tsuite, 1943.; 2 notebooks.; Sakai's study on Tenno. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Eisenhower/Yoshida, 1954. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - U.S. news-letter, 1977. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Tenno o dosuru,..., 1943. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Sankei shimbun, 1969-1977. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Tokyo shimbun, 1948. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Campus riot, prostitution, etc., 1960s. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Ryukyu Islands (press release), 1961, 1962. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Nashonaru puresu ni okeru, 1965. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Draft Japanese peace treaty, 1951-1972.; Sato soridaijin enzetsu. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Chappaquiddick, etc., 1969. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - J.F.K., his family.. .etc, 1964, 1965. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Nixon's inner circle, etc., 1966, 1969. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Emperor, 1971. (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Japan commends S.C. athletes, 1935, 1972, etc. (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - U.S. Army, Green Beret, etc., 1967-1972. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - China, 1939[?]. (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Jerusalem, 1936. (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Guadalajara, 1937. (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Galicia mantir, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - The Times, Egypt number, 1937 January 26. (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - La guerra civil 32 dibujos..., n.d. (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Mundo grafico, 1937. (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - The Suez Canal: map and notes (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Dibujos de la Guerra, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 9)